KYLE ABARQUEZ

UX/UI DESIGN FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

Kabarquez@gmail.com

https://kyleabarguez.github.io/Kyle-Abarguez-Design/

Rancho Santa Margarita, CA

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I'm a UX/UI designer passionate about solving problems through thoughtful & stylish design.

I'm passionate about designing and creating interactive digital products with a comprehensive user-centered design process from user research to beautiful pixels. I love breaking down problems to their core and constructing solutions to those problems in a thoughtful and methodical manner. In order to ensure a smooth workflow between designer and developer I believe that it is important to understand every step of the creative processfrom design to code.

SKILLS

- Responsive Web Design
- UX/UI Design
- Wireframing / Prototyping
- **User Testing**
- **PSD** to Code Workflow
- **CSS Animations**
- SVG Art / Iconography
- HTML Emails
- Web Asset Design
- Interaction Design

TECHNOLOGIES

- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Photoshop
- Sketch App
- **Flinto**
- Principle
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Bootstrap 4
- **JavaScript**

EDUCATION

2011 - 2015 **BA in Studio Art**

> Design fundamentals, art theory, and traditional art mediums such as painting, photography, and sculpture. It is here where my appreciation for the arts and design really grew.

University of California, Irvine

Feb - Aug 2018

UX/UI Bootcamp Completion

User research, testing, user-centric design, front-end technologies, and much more. I worked with team members to create projects starting from research leading all the way up to coded prototypes.

University of California, Irvine **Dept. of Continuing Education**

2016 - Current

Self Learning

HTML, CSS, and JavaScript through multiple online courses. I continue to strengthen my design and development skills through further research as well as personal projects.

Online Courses & Tutorials

EXPERIENCE

2015 - 2017

English Second Language Instructor

I was the English teacher for 2 elementary schools in Mito, Japan. I taught Kindergarten through 6th grade. I taught about 30 classes per week in addition to the time dedicated to lesson planning and material construction. It was a fantastic experience that greatly helped to mold my strong work ethic.

Ibaraki Prefectural Government Japan

2018 - Current

Web Design / UX/UI / Front End Dev. Self Study

Led end-to-end design and development on concept projects for mobile applications, website redesigns, an interactive conference website, emails, and more. View projects at kyleabarquez.github.io/Portfolio.

Freelance Work